Register of the John F. Russell collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- General Subject File, 1930-1973 (Boxes 1-26)
  - Religion (general) (Box-folder 22: 11-12)
    Mainly re communist influence in churches.
  - Reporter (Box-folder 22: 13)
  - Rosicrucians (Box-folder 22: 14)
  - Sabotage (Box-folder 22: 15)
    Includes material on Vietnam War-era advocacy of sabotage.
  - Sailors' Union of the Pacific (Box-folder 22: 16)
  - Secret societies (Box-folder 22: 17)
  - Smith Act (Alien Registration Act) (Box-folder 23: 1)
    Mainly issuances of defense organizations for persons prosecuted under the Act.
  - Social Frontier (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Socialist Labor Party (Box-folder 23: 3)
    Includes numerous leaflets issued by the Party and material on the New York Labor News Company.
  - Socialist Party (Box-folder 23: 4)
    Includes material on the Call Association.
  - Socialist Workers Party (Box-folder 23: 5)
    Includes material on Pioneer Publishers.
  - Society for Ethical Culture (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Southern Regional Council (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Soviet Union (Box-folder 23: 9-11)
    Includes 1959-1961 press releases of the Soviet Embassy in the United States.
  - Spain (Box-folder 23: 12)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (Box-folder 23: 13)
  - Students for a Democatic Society (Box-folder 23: 14)
    Includes 1969 U.S. Army report on infiltration of industry by the Society.
  - Students for Democratic Action (Box-folder 23: 15)
    Includes organizational manual.
  - Subversive organizations (Box-folder 24: 1)
    Lists compiled by the U.S. Department of Justice, the U.S. Civil Service Commission, the U.S. Army, and private sources.
  - Sunpapers (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Teachers Union (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Time (magazine) (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Trade (Box-folder 24: 5)
    Mainly re East-West trade.
  - Trade Union Unity League (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Ukraine (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Unemployed (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Unitarians (Box-folder 24: 10)
  - United Automobile Workers Union (Box-folder 24: 11)
  - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (Box-folder 24: 12)
  - United Nations (Box-folder 24: 13)
    Includes material on organizations supporting the United Nations.
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (Unesco) (Box-folder 24: 14)
  - United Packinghouse Workers Union (Box-folder 24: 15)
  - United States, Department of State (Box-folder 24: 16)
    Includes material on communist influence within the Department and a transcript of a 1949 round table discussion on American policy in China held within the Department.
  - United States, Department of State (cont'd.) (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - United States National Student Association (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - United World Federalists (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - University Place Book Shop (New York City) (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Veterans (general) (Box-folder 25: 5)
    Re communist influence among veterans.
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Veterans of the O.S.S. (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Vietnam War (Box-folder 25: 8)
    Mainly re protest movements. Includes Vietnam work-in organizer's manual.
  - War Resisters League (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Washington Committee for Democratic Action (Washington, D.C.) (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Washington Cooperative Bookshop (Washington, D.C.) (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Washington Interracial Workshop (Washington, D.C.) (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - Weavers (musical group) (Box-folder 25: 13)
  - Win the Peace Committee (Box-folder 25: 14)
  - Women (general) (Box-folder 25: 15)
    Mainly re communist influence among women.
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box-folder 25: 16)
  - Workers Bookshop (New York City) (Box-folder 25: 17)
  - Workers Defense League (Box-folder 25: 18)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth (Box-folder 25: 19)
  - World Federation of Trade Unions (Box-folder 25: 20)
  - World Goodwill (organization) (Box-folder 25: 21)
  - World Health Organization (Box-folder 25: 22)
  - World Marxist Review (Box-folder 25: 23)
  - World Peace Council (Box-folder 25: 24)
  - World Security Workshop (Box-folder 25: 25)
    Transcript of 1947 radio broadcast.
  - World Spiritual Communist Congress for Peace and Unity (1951: London) (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - World Youth and Student Festival (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Writers Workshops of Arts, Sciences and Professions (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Young Communist League (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Young People's Conference for Peace (1950: Baltimore) (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Young Socialist League (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Young Women's Christian Associations (Box-folder 26: 7)
    Re communist influence within the Associations.
  - Youth (general) (Box-folder 26: 8)
    Re communist influence within youth.
  - Yugoslavia (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 26: 10)
- Individual Subject File, 1942-1965 (Boxes 26-31)
  Dossiers, biographical data, memoranda, reports, letters, circulated documents, clippings and other printed matter, and typed copies of printed matter relating to suspect individuals.
  - Acheson, Dean (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Adler, Solomon (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Antonini, Luigi (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - Atkinson, Brooks (Box-folder 26: 14)
  - Baker, Josephine (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - Ballard, Frederic A. (Box-folder 26: 16)
  - Bambrick, J. J. (Box-folder 26: 17)
  - Barr, Stringfellow (Box-folder 26: 18)
  - Baruch, Bernard (Box-folder 26: 19)
  - Bellanca, Dorothy (Box-folder 26: 20)
  - Benton, William (Box-folder 26: 21)
  - Berle, Adolph A. (Box-folder 26: 22)
  - Berman, Averill (Box-folder 26: 23)
  - Bernstein, Leonard (Box-folder 26: 24)
  - Bettis, Valerie (Box-folder 26: 25)
  - Blanshard, Paul (Box-folder 26: 26)
  - Bodde, Derk (Box-folder 26: 27)
  - Boyer, Richard O. (Box-folder 26: 28)
  - Breslaw, Joseph (Box-folder 26: 29)
  - Bridges, Harry. (Box-folder 26: 30)
    Includes U.S. Immigration and Naturalization Service hearing proceedings
  - Brotman, Herman B. (Box-folder 26: 31)
  - Browder, Irene (Box-folder 26: 32)
  - Bunche, Ralph (Box-folder 26: 33)
  - Burke, Robert (Box-folder 26: 34)
  - Cantor, Eddie (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Carp, Sam (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - Cerf, Bennett (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Chaplin, Charlie (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Childs, Marquis (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Coe, Virginius Frank (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Coffin, Henry Sloan (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Commager, Henry Steele (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Conroy, Jack (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Crane, Henry Hitt (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Crichton, Kyle S. (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Crosby, John (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Currie, Lauchlin (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Dahlberg, Edwin T. (Box-folder 27: 14)
  - Davies, A. Powell (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - Davis, Elmer (Box-folder 27: 16)
  - Davis, Hallie F. (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - Davis, Jerome (Box-folder 27: 18)
  - Day, Dorothy (Box-folder 27: 19)
  - Dean, Arthur H. (Box-folder 27: 20)
  - Dean, Vera Micheles (Box-folder 27: 21)
  - Dewey, John (Box-folder 27: 22)
  - Dimitrov, Georgi (Box-folder 27: 23)
  - Dirba, Charles (Charles Lapin) (Box-folder 27: 24)
  - Doriot, Georges F. (Box-folder 27: 25)
  - Douglas, James M. (Box-folder 27: 26)
  - Douglas, Paul H. (Box-folder 27: 27)
  - Douglas, William O. (Box-folder 27: 28)
  - Downes, Olin (Box-folder 27: 29)
  - Dubinsky, David (Box-folder 27: 30)
  - Duran, Gustavo (Box-folder 27: 31)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box-folder 27: 32)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box-folder 27: 33)
  - Evans, Giles (Box-folder 27: 34)
  - Fadiman, Clifton (Box-folder 27: 35)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt (Box-folder 27: 36)
  - Feinstone, Morris (Box-folder 27: 37)
  - Fenn, Don Frank (Box-folder 27: 38)
  - Ferrer, Jose (Box-folder 27: 39)
  - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt (Box-folder 27: 40)
  - Fisher, Adrian (Box-folder 27: 41)
  - Fisher, Dorothy C. (Box-folder 27: 42)
  - Fletcher, Joseph (Box-folder 27: 43)
  - Foreman, Clark H. (Box-folder 27: 44)
  - Foster, William C. (Box-folder 27: 45)
  - Foster, William Z. (Box-folder 27: 46)
    Includes mimeographed transcript of Foster's book Toward Soviet America
  - France, Royal Wilbur (Box-folder 27: 47)
  - Frankfeld, Philip (Box-folder 27: 48)
  - Fried, Louis H. (Box-folder 27: 49)
  - Gannett, Betty (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Geer, Will (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Geisler, Hans (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Gilford, Jack (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Gillars, Mildred (Axis Sally) (Box-folder 28: 5)
    Includes lengthy typescript by Hilma Blai, "The Propaganda Methods of Axis Sally"
  - Glasser, Harold (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Gold, Ben (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - Goleniewski, Michael (Grand Duke Aleksei Romanov) (Box-folder 28: 8)
    Includes legal deposition
  - Goudsmit, Samuel A. (Box-folder 28: 9)
  - Graves, Mortimer (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Greenberg, Harry (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Greenberg, Michael (Box-folder 28: 12)
  - Gropper, William (Box-folder 28: 13)
  - Gyorgy, Andrew (Box-folder 28: 14)
  - Halperin, Maurice (Box-folder 28: 15)
  - Hamlin, Bryan (Box-folder 28: 16)
  - Harno, Albert J. (Box-folder 28: 17)
  - Harrington, Donald (Box-folder 28: 18)
  - Harris, M. Lafayette (Box-folder 28: 19)
  - Harris, William H. (Box-folder 28: 20)
    Includes text of legal complaint in libel and slander lawsuit against the American Legion
  - Haywood, Allan (Box-folder 28: 21)
  - Hemingway, Ernest (Box-folder 28: 22)
  - Hendon, Louis (Box-folder 28: 23)
  - Hennacy, Ammon (Box-folder 28: 24)
  - Herrick, Elinore M. (Box-folder 28: 25)
  - Hersey, John (Box-folder 28: 26)
  - Higginbotham, William A. (Box-folder 28: 27)
  - Higgins, Arthur (Box-folder 28: 28)
  - Hill, David Lawrence (Box-folder 28: 29)
  - Hillman, Sidney (Box-folder 28: 30)
  - Hinton, Samuel (Box-folder 28: 31)
  - Hiss, Alger (Box-folder 28: 32)
  - Hiss, Donald (Box-folder 28: 33)
  - Hochman, Julius (Box-folder 28: 34)
  - Hodgin, David R. (Box-folder 28: 35)
  - Holland, Kenneth (Box-folder 28: 36)
  - Hollander, Louis (Box-folder 28: 37)
  - Holliday, Judy (Box-folder 28: 38)
  - Holmes, John Haynes (Box-folder 28: 39)
  - Hornbeck, Stanley (Box-folder 28: 40)
  - Hughes, Paul H. (Box-folder 28: 41)
  - Jaffe, Philip J. (Box-folder 28: 42)
  - Jerome, V. J. (Box-folder 28: 43)
  - Jessup, Philip C. (Box-folder 28: 44)
    Includes extensive documentary publication by the office of Senator Joseph R. McCarthy
  - Johnson, Charles S. (Box-folder 28: 45)
  - Jones, E. Stanley (Box-folder 28: 46)
  - Kaplan, Irving (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Karr, David (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Kay, Helen (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Kennan, George F. (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Kennedy, A. J. (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Kenny, Robert W. (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Kent, Rockwell (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Kern, Paul (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Kilpatrick, William (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred. (Box-folder 29: 10)
    Includes critical report on Kohlberg by the Christian Alliance against Illuminism and a letter in his defense by W. Fairfield Peterson
  - Kramer, Charles (Krivitsky) (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - Krizek, Joseph F. (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - Kroll, Jack (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Lamont, Corliss (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Lasswell, Harold D. (Box-folder 29: 15)
  - Lattimore, Owen. (Box-folder 29: 16)
    Includes pamphlet Lattimore the Scholar
  - Lattimore, Richmond (Box-folder 29: 17)
  - Lewis, Marx (Box-folder 29: 18)
  - Lippmann, Walter (Box-folder 29: 19)
  - Livingston, David (Box-folder 29: 20)
  - Lorch, Lee (Box-folder 29: 21)
  - Lovett, Robert Morss (Box-folder 29: 22)
  - Lynd, Robert (Box-folder 29: 23)
  - McConnell, Francis J. (Box-folder 29: 24)
  - McGrath, Frank R. (Box-folder 29: 25)
  - Mackay, John A. (Box-folder 29: 26)
  - McMichael, Jack R. (Box-folder 29: 27)
  - McWilliams, Carey (Box-folder 29: 28)
  - Mailer, Norman (Box-folder 29: 29)
  - Marcantonio, Vito (Box-folder 29: 30)
  - March, Frederic (Box-folder 29: 31)
  - Martin, Robert P. (Box-folder 29: 32)
  - Marzani, Carl (Box-folder 29: 33)
  - Mather, Kirtley (Box-folder 29: 34)
  - Matles, James J. (Box-folder 29: 35)
  - Michelson, Clarina (Box-folder 29: 36)
  - Michener, Lew H. (Box-folder 29: 37)
  - Miller, Abraham (Box-folder 29: 38)
  - Miller, Arthur (Box-folder 29: 39)
  - Miller, Clyde R. (Box-folder 29: 40)
  - Mills, Saul (Box-folder 29: 41)
  - Mink, George (Box-folder 29: 42)
  - Mitchell, George S. (Box-folder 29: 43)
  - Moore, John Milton (Box-folder 29: 44)
  - Morrison, Herbert S. (Box-folder 29: 45)
  - Morse, Wayne. (Box-folder 30: 1)
    Includes lengthy study by the Oregon State Republican Party Central Committee
  - Moulton, Arthur (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - Mudd, Stuart (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Muir, Jean (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Murray, Philip (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Murrow, Edward R. (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Myers, Frederick N. (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Nagler, Isadore (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - Odets, Clifford (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert. (Box-folder 30: 11)
    Includes U.S. Atomic Energy Commission findings and recommendations
  - Osman, Arthur (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley (Box-folder 30: 13)
  - Paley, Jack (Box-folder 30: 14)
  - Pearson, Drew (Box-folder 30: 15)
  - Pemrose, Dr. (Box-folder 30: 16)
  - Permutter, Samuel (Box-folder 30: 17)
  - Peterson, Esther E. (Box-folder 30: 18)
  - Potofsky, Jacob S. (Box-folder 30: 19)
  - Quill, Michael (Box-folder 30: 20)
  - Reid, Ira de A. (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Remington, William (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Reuben, William A. (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Reuther, Walter P. (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Rice, Elmer (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Rieve, Emil (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Robeson, Paul. (Box-folder 31: 7)
    Includes material on 1949 Peekskill, New York, riot
  - Robins, Raymond (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Rose, Alex (Olesh Royz) (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Rosenberg, Anna M. (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel (Box-folder 31: 11)
  - Rossen, Robert (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - Roth, Andrew (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Rustin, Bayard (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - Salisbury, Harrison (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Saroyan, William (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - Schappes, Morris U. (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Box-folder 31: 18)
  - Schlesinger, Emil (Box-folder 31: 19)
  - Schneiderman, Rose (Box-folder 31: 20)
  - Schneiderman, William (Box-folder 31: 21)
  - Schultz, Benjamin (Box-folder 31: 22)
  - Schuman, Frederick L. (Box-folder 31: 23)
  - Service, John S. (Box-folder 31: 24)
  - Seymour, Whitney North (Box-folder 31: 25)
  - Shaw, Irwin (Box-folder 31: 26)
  - Shipler, Guy E. (Box-folder 31: 27)
  - Shore, Samuel (Box-folder 31: 28)
  - Sinatra, Frank (Box-folder 31: 29)
  - Siporin, Seymour (Box-folder 31: 30)
  - Smedley, Agnes (Box-folder 31: 31)
  - Smith, Edwin S. (Box-folder 31: 32)
  - Spector, Nathaniel (Box-folder 31: 33)
  - Stern, Alfred K. (Box-folder 31: 34)
  - Stevens, Wallace (Box-folder 31: 35)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (Box-folder 31: 36)
  - Stewart, Annalee (Box-folder 31: 37)
  - Stewart, Maxwell (Box-folder 31: 38)
  - Strebel, Gustave A. (Box-folder 31: 39)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Box-folder 31: 40)
  - Thompson, John B. (Box-folder 31: 41)
  - Tillich, Paul (Box-folder 31: 42)
  - Tydings, Millard (Box-folder 31: 43)
  - Umhey, Frederick F. (Box-folder 31: 44)
  - Van Doren, Carl (Box-folder 31: 45)
  - Veblen, Oswald (Box-folder 31: 46)
  - Vincent, John Carter (Box-folder 31: 47)
  - Vladeck, Baruch Charney (Box-folder 31: 48)
  - Wahl, David Ralph (Box-folder 31: 49)
  - Wainwright, Juan Pablo (Box-folder 31: 50)
  - Ward, Harry F. (Box-folder 31: 51)
  - Warne, Colston E. (Box-folder 31: 52)
  - Watson, Goodwin B. (Box-folder 31: 53)
  - Webber, Charles C. (Box-folder 31: 54)
  - Weinstein, Murray (Box-folder 31: 55)
  - Weinstock, Louis (Box-folder 31: 56)
  - Weintraub, David (Box-folder 31: 57)
  - Wheeler, George S. (Box-folder 31: 58)
  - White, Harry Dexter (Box-folder 31: 59)
    Includes statement by J. Edgar Hoover.
  - Williams, Claude C. (Box-folder 31: 60)
  - Witt, Nathan (Box-folder 31: 61)
  - Zaritsky, Max (Box-folder 31: 62)
  - Zimmerman, Charles S. (Box-folder 31: 63)
- United States Department of Defense Issuances, 1943-1970 (Boxes 32-36)
  Instructional materials, manuals, pamphlets, bibliographies, and directives.
  - United States Army Counter Intelligence Corps issuances, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 32: 1-4)
    Typescript and mimeographed instructional manuals, directives, and documentary texts, relating primarily to communism in the United States. Also includes material on Counter Intelligence Corps history during World War II, and on adjudication of personnel security cases
  - United States Department of Defense manuals, regulations and directives re military security, industrial security, personnel security clearance, and safeguarding classified information, 1948-1970 (Box-folder 33: 1-4)
  - United States Army Western Defense Command mimeographed reports on Japanese organizations in the United States, 1944 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - United States Army Far East Command Military Intelligence Section printed translation of Japanese documents on the Richard Sorge spy ring, 1947 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - United States War Department pamphlets, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    Includes Intelligence Division reference pamphlet on the Soviet Union
  - United States War Department and Department of the Army field manuals, 1943-1965 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - United States Department of Defense Office of Armed Forces Information and Education pamphlets, 1953-1966 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    Includes "Know Your Communist Enemy" series; The U.S. Fighting Man's Code; The Promise of the New Asia
  - United States Department of Defense miscellaneous pamphlets, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    Includes summary of Militant Liberty Program
  - United States Industrial College of the Armed Forces instructional pamphlets, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - United States Industrial College of the Armed Forces instructional pamphlets (cont'd.), 1961-1965 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - United States Army Command and General Staff College reference work, Nuclear Weapons Employment, 1958 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - United States Army miscellaneous pamphlets, 1954-1967 (Box-folder 35: 3-4)
    Includes bibliographies and reference works on the Soviet Union and China
  - United States Army miscellaneous pamphlets (cont'd.), 1954-1967 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - United States Air Force pamphlets, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 36: 2)
    Includes Air War College study, "The Air Force and National Security Policy"
- United States Federal Bureau of Investigation Issuances, 1946-1966 (Box 36)
  - Press releases, speeches, bulletins, pamphlets, and journal articles, many by J. Edgar Hoover (Box-folder 36: 3-4)
- United States Subversive Activities Control Board Issuances, 1953-1957 (Boxes 36-37)
  Reports and recommended decisions.
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - California Labor School (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Civil Rights Congress (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A. (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - Jefferson School of Social Science (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Labor Youth League (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - United May Day Committee (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (Box-folder 37: 5)
- United States Congressional Issuances, 1931-1976 (Boxes 37-44)
  Congressional hearing transcripts, reports, bills, speeches, and press releases relating primarily to communism and subversion issues.
  - General, 1942-1962
    - Bills to amend legislation re communism and internal security (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - House Committee on Un-American Activities (Box-folder 38: 1)
      Press releases and speech by committee members. Includes some printed matter about the Committee.
    - McCarthy, Senator Joseph R. (Box-folder 38: 2)
      Speeches and articles by McCarthy. Includes The Party of Betrayal, pamphlet reprinting documents submitted by McCarthy to the Senate; typescript summary of points in McCarthy's book, The Fight for America; and some printed matter about McCarthy.
    - Appendix A. (Box-folder 38: 3)
      Photocopy of lengthy appendix to unidentified Congressional study of the Communist Party, U.S.A.
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 38: 4)
      Speeches, excerpts from the Congressional Record, and miscellaneous printed matter re Congressional investigation of communism.
  - Congressional committee hearing transcripts and reports
    - United States, Congress, House, Special Committee to Investigate Communist Activities in the United States (Fish Committee), 1931 (Box-folder 39: 1)
      Includes index.
    - United States, Congress, House, Committee on Un-American Activities
      - 1940 (Box-folder 39: 2)
      - 1941 (Box-folder 39: 3)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 39: 4)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 39: 5)
      - 1946 (Box-folder 39: 6)
      - 1947 (Box-folder 39: 7)
      - 1948 (Box-folder 39: 8)
      - 1949 (Box-folder 40: 1)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 40: 2)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 40: 3)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 40: 4)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 40: 5)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 40: 6)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 40: 7)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 40: 8)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 40: 9)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 40: 10)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 41: 1)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 41: 2)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 41: 3)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 41: 4)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 41: 5)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 41: 6)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - United States, Congress, House (miscellaneous committees and whole House prints)
      - 1945 (Box-folder 41: 8)
      - 1947 (Box-folder 41: 9)
      - 1948 (Box-folder 41: 10)
      - 1949 (Box-folder 41: 11)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 41: 12)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 41: 13)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 42: 1)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - United States, Congress, Senate, Committee on the Judiciary
      Primarily Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws.
      - 1950 (Box-folder 42: 3)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 42: 4)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 42: 5)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 42: 6)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 42: 7)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 42: 8)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 42: 9)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 42: 10)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 42: 11)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 42: 12)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 42: 13)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 43: 1)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 43: 2)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 43: 3)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 43: 4)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 43: 5)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 43: 6)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 43: 7)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 43: 8)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 43: 9)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 43: 10)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 43: 11)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 43: 12)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 43: 13)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 43: 14)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 43: 15)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 43: 16)
    - United States, Congress, Senate (miscellaneous committees and whole Senate prints)
      - 1946 (Box-folder 44: 1)
      - 1948 (Box-folder 44: 2)
      - 1949 (Box-folder 44: 3)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 44: 4)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 44: 5)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 44: 6)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 44: 7)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 44: 8)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 44: 9)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 44: 10)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 44: 11)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 44: 12)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 44: 13)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 44: 14)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 44: 15)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 44: 16)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 44: 17)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 44: 18)
- United States Information Agency Issuances, 1950-1969 (Boxes 45-49)
  Bulletins, reports, and article reprints relating to international communism. Includes "Backgrounder on Communism" series.